Matt Nelsen

 \bowtie

mattnelsen95@gmail.com



matthewnelsen.com



github.com/m-nelsen



linkedin.com/in/matthew-nelsen

Summary

Full-stack web developer with over 3 years of experience creating UIs, optimizing web pages, condensing APIs into usable information for end-users, and integrating third-party platforms into web sites. I enjoy working with React and Node, but I'm always willing to learn more technologies.

Professional Experience

Digital Engineer, Gray Television Inc (Oct 2020 - Present)

- Designed and developed React.js components used across 160+ local news stations
- Optimized speed and size of web pages for better user experience and SEO
- Worked closely with operations team to quickly address bugs affecting users
- Integrated third party advertising and analytic platforms such as Google Analytics
- Created tools to improve the workflow efficiency of company employees

Web Developer, Customer Scout (Oct 2019 - May 2020)

- Designed and developed web pages with bootstrap for automotive dealerships
- Maintained websites on a variety of CMS platforms including WordPress
- Implemented SEO strategies that helped place clients in top search engine rankings
- Coordinated with coworkers to deliver time-sensitive information during COVID pandemic

Technical Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- SCSS
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- React

- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- SQL/NoSQL
- Bootstrap
- Git

- RESTful API
- lest
- CI/CD
- SEO
- Responsive Design
- Linux

Education

Bachelor of Science | **Information Systems** (2015 – 2019) – Northern Arizona University Certificate | **Accounting** (2015 – 2019) – Northern Arizona University

Projects

Custom Embed Editor

 Developed an application using React.js that integrates into a CMS's article builder to provide additional functionality including polling, video selection, and live stream selection